# **ALINA NANU**



### CONTACT

+40743535136



🗪 nanualinav@gmail.com



www Portfolio Website

#### PROFILE

I am a highly motivated developer with a passion for creating exceptional user experiences. My journey in the world of technology began with mobile app development where I was building applications for iPhone and iPad devices.

As a developer with a desire for continuous growth and learning, I am now shifting my focus to Frontend Development.

My solid foundation in iOS development has equipped me with strong problem-solving abilities, a keen eye for detail, and a commitment to delivering high-quality code.

## EDUCATION AND TRAINING

### Front-End Engineer Career Path, Codecademy

02/2023 View Certificate

#### Master's degree in Computer Engineering

"Stefan cel Mare" University, Faculty of Electrical **Engineering and Computer** Science

Suceava | 10/2016 - 07/2018

#### Bachelor's degree in Computer **Engineering**

"Stefan cel Mare" University, Faculty of Electrical **Engineering and Computer** Science

Suceava | 10/2012 - 07/2016

## EXPERIENCE

## OSF Academy Salesforce Commerce Cloud React Developer

OSF Digital • Bucharest • 06/11/2023 - 11/12/2023

- Experience with PWA Kit and Headless Architecture;
- Completed practical tasks using React.js, Chakra UI, PWA Kit, Git and Web Development concepts;
- Engaged in a collaborative code review process;
- Involved in bi-weekly progress scrum meetings;

## Front-End Developer Training Program

KREATIVSTORM • 07/2023 - 08/2023

#### View Certificate

- Gained proficiency in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript;
- Completed assigned individual and group projects;
- Used GitHub for code repositories;

#### KEY SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- React and Redux
- Swift
- Git and Version Control
- Networking (RESTful APIs, JSON, XML)
- Firebase
- ChakraUI
- Headless Architecture
- Testing and Debugging
- SEO Optimization
- Adobe Suite (Photoshop,
  Illustrator, Xd)

## LANGUAGES

Romanian

English

Russian

- Participated in peer code reviews and followed industry best practices;
- · Attended scheduled training sessions and workshops.

#### iOS Software Engineer

Ness Digital Engineering • Iasi • 04/2021 – 05/2022

- Experience with Video Content Consumption through HLS Streaming: IP VOD, IP Linear (LiveTV), downloaded content:
- Designed and maintained high performance, reusable, and reliable Swift code;
- Investigated and fixed issues reported by users or identified through testing and monitoring processes;
- Used Jenkins for the process of continuously integration and continuous delivery cycle;
- Used JIRA for bug tracking, Fork for Git interactions and code management;
- Worked in Agile environment;
- Attended demo calls with the client, daily stand-up meetings, retrospective meetings, sprint planning, knowledge transfer sessions.

#### iOS Developer

OSF Digital • Remote • 08/2016 - 05/2020

- Experience with developing applications for iPhone and iPad devices;
- Troubleshooting, diagnosing, and supporting mobile application development;
- Used native iOS frameworks, including CoreData, MapKit, UIKit, Foundation, ARKit;
- Worked with Verifone, Square Reader devices for encrypting and validating card payments, including Apple Pay;
- Experience with iBeacon technology;
- Prepared applications for release on the App Store, including creating certificates and provisioning profiles;
- Used JIRA for bug tracking, Sourcetree for Git interactions and code management;
- Ecommerce SDK Development Experience.